A Finding Aid to the Forbes Watson Papers, 1840-1967, bulk 1900-1960, in the Archives of American Art AAA.watsforb
Archives of American Art
- U.S. Treasury Department records, 1926-1945; Series 4; (Boxes 3-6, 14, 17, OV 21; 3.4 linear feet)
  - Wrtitings and Lists, 1934-1945; 4.5
    - "The Artist and His People" and "The Artists' War Message,", undated (Box 5, Folder 74)
    - "Art Projects of the U.S. Treasury Department,", undated (Box 5, Folder 75)
    - "Bridge the Gap,", undated (Box 5, Folder 76)
      (for the Colonial Dames)
    - "Dignity of Wages," "Educational and Wealth-Producing Advantages of Art in Federal Buildings," and "The Fate of Unheralded Acts,", undated (Box 5, Folder 77)
    - "Federal Encouagement and Private Support of Art,", undated (Box 5, Folder 78)
    - "Federalizing the American Artist,", undated (Box 5, Folder 79)
    - "Five Months of Federal Act,", undated (Box 5, Folder 80)
    - "Glycerine Tears," "Government and Art in the United States," and "Edward Laning Drawings,", undated (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - Talks, undated (Box 5, Folder 82)
      (In Nashville and for National Women's Democratic Club Talk)
    - "The National World War Institute," Painting a People's War," "Paintings from the United States," "Paying the Artists' Bills,", undated (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - "The People and Their Art,", undated (Box 5, Folder 84)
    - "Procurement Architecture,", undated; (3 folders) (Box 5, Folder 85-87)
      (Includes Photographs)
    - "The Public Works of Art Project: A New Deal for the Artists,", undated (Box 5, Folder 88)
    - "The Section of Fine Arts," and "Sergeant Glen Rounds,", undated (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - "A Survey Guide Containing Suggestions for a Survey to be Made by Every Branch of the A.W.U.W. for the Purpose of Bringing the Artist and the Community into More Effective Relationship,", undated (Box 5, Folder 90)
    - "To Know the Art of Mural Painting in America Everybody Finds it Necessary to Visit the National Capitol," and "The treasury Department Art Projects,", undated (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - "Treasury Department Section of Fine Arts 1933-1938," "Uncle Sam the Art Collector," and "The Uses of Art,", undated (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - "Visiting Artists Praise Exhibition of Works by Section of Fine Arts," "War Art," and "Washington's New Art,", undated (Box 5, Folder 93)
    - "We Did Not Need a Bombing," and Woodstock Talk, undated (Box 5, Folder 94)
    - "This About America,", 1934 (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - "Easel Paintings Supplement Treasury Department Mural Projects,", 1936 (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Talks, 1936-1938 (Box 5, Folder 97)
      (At Howard University and Worcester Museum of Art)
    - "Art in Federal Buildings,", 1938 (Box 5, Folder 98)
      (Talk Delivered at the White House)
    - "This Art Belongs to You,", 1938; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 99-100)
    - Lecture at American Association of University Women, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 101)
    - "Painting and Sculpture Designed for Federal Buildings,", 1939 (Box 5, Folder 102)
      (Introduction for Exhibition Catalog)
    - "Edward Bruce,", 1940 (Box 5, Folder 103)
    - Lecture at National Mural Painters Society, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 104)
    - Phillips Gallery Talk, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 105)
    - American Institute of Decorators Talk, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 106)
    - John Herron Institute Talk, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 107)
    - "Catalogue,", 1942 (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - "Art in War,", 1942 (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - "Introduction: Wartime Painting," and "Foreward,", 1944 (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - "The Function of a War Museum,", 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 111)
      (Richmond Lecture to the Tuckahoe Women's Club)
    - "Public Works Art Project," "The Section of Fine Arts," "A Short Account of the Background of the Procurement Division," and "Artists!...Please Note,", undated; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 112-113)
      (by Edward Bruce)
    - "Six Month Study of Art in the United States,", 1940 (Box 5, Folder 114)
      (by Charlotte R. Partridge)
    - Writings on the History of the Section of the Fine Arts, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Notes and Writings, 1936-1943, undated; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 2-3)
  - Printed Material, 1926-1944; 4.6
    Found are clippings, copies of The Bulletin, press releases, exhibition catalogs, materials relating to Art Guide, and published works.
    - Clippings, 1926-1939; (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 4-7)
    - The Bulletin, 1935-1940; (5 folders) (Box 6, Folder 8-12)
    - Press Releases, 1933-1943; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
    - Exhibition Catalogs (Box 6)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Colorado Springs Fine Arts Center, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Mural Designs Executed Under the Federal Works Agency, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Exhibition of Photographs of Murals and Sculpture, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - National Exhibition of Art by the Public Works of Art Project, Whitney Museum of American Art, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Mural Designers and Sculpture Models by Appointed and Competing Artists Submitted for Federal Buildings Projects, Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Sculpture and Paintings for Federal Buildings, Whitney Museum of American Art, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Painting and Sculpture for Federal Buildings, Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Painting and Sculpture Designed for Federal Buildings, Corcoran Gallery of Art, 1939 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Mural Designs for Federal Buildings, National Gallery of Canada, Ottawa and Whitney Museum of American Art, 1940; (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 24-26)
      - 200 American Watercolors, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - An Exhibtion of 200 American Water Colors, National Gallery of Art, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - Two Hundred American Water Colors, Whitney Museum of American Art, 1941 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - American Artists' Record of War and Defense, National Gallery of Art, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      - The Edward Bruce Memorial Collection, 1943 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Art Guide, 1938; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 32-33)
      (Includes a mock-up and copies for the Justice Building and for the Post Office)
    - Art in Federal Buildings, Volume I: Mural Designs by Edward Bruce and Forbes Watson, 1936; (Oversized material housed in Box 17) (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1936-1944, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Oversized Art in Federal Buildings, Volume I: Mural Designs by Edward Bruce and Forbes Watson, 1936; (from Box 6, F34) (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, 1934, undated; 4.7
    Found are photographs taken at receptions, radio talks, events, and of murals.
    - Presentation of Painting of National Archives Building by Dorsey Doniphan, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Radio Talk with John Dewey, Robert LaFollette, Jr., and Sumner Welles, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Procurement Division Luncheon, undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Department of Justice Reception, undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Exhibition at Art Guild of Washington, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Washington Post Office Murals, undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Regional Directors and Washington Administrative Staff of Public Works of Art Project, 1934 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Scrapbooks, 1944-1945; 4.8
    Found is one scrapbook from the "Army at War" exhibition held in Milwaukee, Wisconsin.
    - Scrapbook, 1944-1945 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- File for Pepsi-Cola Company's Third Annual Exhibition Paintings of the Year, 1946; Series 5; (Box 6; 5 folders)
  This file concerns the Pepsi-Cola Company's Third Annual Exhibition at the National Academy of Design in which Watson was interested after his service in the U. S. Treasury Department. It contains a prospectus, an exhibition catalog and artists' statements.
  - Prospectus and Exhibition Catalog, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Artists' Statements, 1946; (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 45-48)
- Artist/Patron Files, 1840-1967; Series 6; (Box 6-9, 15, OV 21; 2.8 linear feet)
  The Artist/Patron Files contain reference material including notes, typescripts, scattered art work, printed material including exhibition catalogs, and photographs concerning painters, sculptors, photographers, dancers, composers, authors, art collectors, art dealers, and museum administrators. Many files include notable portrait photographs and of artists at work, which are noted at the folder level. A file for Edward Rowan includes a letter from Bruce describing his philosophy regarding the PWAP and the Section of Fine Arts. A file for Constantin Brancusi contains legal documents concerning U. S. Customs vs. Brancusi. A file for John Gadsby Chapman contains a booklet The Picture: Baptism of Pocahontas (1840). Notable photographers includea photograph of Andrew Dasburg by Arnold Genthe, a photograph of Eugene McConn by Man Ray, photographs by Ansel Adams of art work by Maurice Sterne, and photographs of New York City by Charles Sheeler.
  - Photographs of Unidentified Individuals, undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Art Work by Unidentified Artists, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 15) (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - George Aarnes; Alanova, undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Washington Allston; Cuno Amiet; Albert André, undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Alexander Archipenko, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Paul Arlt, undated (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Peter Arno with Lupe Velez; Maurice Asselin; Milton Avery, undated (Box 6, Folder 55)
    (Includes portrait photograph of Milton Avery)
  - George and Martin Baer, undated (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Kenneth Bald, undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Alfred H. Barr, Jr., undated (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Erwin J. Barrie, undated (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - A. S. Baylinson; Gifford Beal, undated (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - George Bellows, 1925-1965, undated; (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 61-63)
  - Benjamin Greenstein Benno; Parmello Bianco, undated (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - George Biddle; Henry Billings, undated (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Edwin S. Blashfield, undated (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Robert Blum, 1923, undated; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 67-68)
  - Peter Blume; Ernest Blumenschein, undated (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Simone Brangier Boas, undated (Box 6, Folder 70)
    (Includes portrait photograph)
  - Aaron Bohrod, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 15) (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Louis Bouché, undated (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Clare Shenehon Boyd; Fiske Boyd; Thomas Boyd, 1940, undated (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - Constantin Brancusi, 1927, undated; (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 74-76)
  - Frank Brangwyn; Georges Braque, John Breeze, 1920-1933, undated (Box 6, Folder 77)
    (Includes portrait photograph of Frank Brangwyn)
  - Edgar Britton, undated (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - Manuel Bromberg, undated; (3 folders) (Box 6, Folder 79-81)
  - Alexander Brook, 1930-1952, undated (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - Edward Bruce, 1926-1943, undated; (3 folders; (Box 6, Folder 83-85)
    Includes portrait photograph)
  - Beiamino Bufano; Charles E. Burchfield, 1930, undated (Box 6, Folder 86)
    (Includes portrait photograph of Beiamino Bufano)
  - Henri Burkhard; Edith Woodman Burroughs, undated (Box 6, Folder 87)
  - Stirling Calder; William V. Caldwell, undated (Box 6, Folder 88)
  - William Calfee; Blendon Campbell; Georges Capon, undated (Box 6, Folder 89)
  - Mary Cassatt, 1935, undated; (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 90-91)
  - Marc Chagall; Robert Winthrop Chanler, undated (Box 6, Folder 92)
  - John Gadsby Chapman; William Merritt Chase, 1840-1879, undated (Box 6, Folder 93)
  - Clarence K. Chatterton, 1931, undated (Box 6, Folder 94)
  - Carlos Chavez; Russell Cheney; Nicholas Cikovsky, undated (Box 6, Folder 95)
    (Includes portrait photograph of Carlos Chavez)
  - Glenn O. Coleman, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in OV 21; (Box 6, Folder 96)
  - Alfred Quentin Collins, undated (Box 6, Folder 97)
  - Howard Cook, 1937-1960, undated; (4 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 15) (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
  - J. Halley Cox, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Kenyon Cox, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Alfred DiGiorgio Crimi, 1928-1962, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - John Steuart Curry, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - James D'Agostino, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Andrew Dasburg, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Randall Davey; Jo Davidson, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Arthur B. Davies, 1897-1967, undated; (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 12-15)
  - Gladys Rockmore Davis, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Richard Davis, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Stuart Davis; Roger de La Fresnaye; Charles Demuth, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - André Derain, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Gleb Derujinsky; André Dunoyer de Segonzac, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Maurice de Vlaminck; Henri de Waroquier; Thomas Dewing; Preston Dickinson, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Arthur G. Dove, 1930-1967, undated; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 22-23)
  - Olin Dows, 1936-1946, undated; (4 folders; (Box 7, Folder 24-27)
  - William F. Draper, undated (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Elsie Driggs; Guy Pene Du Bois; Charles Dufresne; Raoul Dufy, undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
    (Includes portrait photograph of Guy Pene Du Bois)
  - Frank D. Duncan, undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Thomas C. Dunn, undated (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Joseph Albert Duveen, 1961, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Elizabeth Boott Duveneck; Frank Duveneck, undated (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Thomas Eakins, 1929, undated (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Stuart Edie, undated (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Paul R. Ellsworth; Max Ernst; Stephen Etnier, undated (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - A. Favori; John Duncan Ferguson, undated (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Hamilton Easter Field, undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Mitchell Fields, undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Ernest Fiene, 1927, undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - James Montgomery Flagg; John Bernard Flannagan; J. L. Forain, undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
    (Includes portrait photograph of James Montgomery Flagg)
  - Juliana Force, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 15; (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - David Fredenthal, 1942-1944, undated; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 43-44)
  - Karl Free, undated (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Daniel Chester French; E. Othon Friesz, undated (Box 7, Folder 46)
    (Includes portrait photograph of Daniel Chester French)
  - Ted R. Gamble, undated (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Emil Ganso; Edith Geiger, undated (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - William J. Glackens, 1920-1949; (5 folders; (Box 7, Folder 49-53)
  - Albert Gleizes; Charles Goeller, undated (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - E. Gondouin; Xavier Gonzales, undated (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - A. Conger Goodyear; Mordecai Gorelik, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 15; (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Harry Gottlieb, undated (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Martha Graham, undated (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Dorothea Greenbaum; M. Gromaire; William Gropper, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 15) (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Chaim Gross; Edwin Booth Grossman; A Guillaumin, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 15) (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Paul Haakon; Robert Hallowell; Hamilton Hamilton, undated (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - George M. Harding, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 15; (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Marie Harriman; George "Pop" Hart, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 15) (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Marsden Hartley, undated (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Rosella Hartman; Leon Hart, undated (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Herbert Haseltine, undated (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Charles Hawthorn; Milton Hebald, undated (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Robert Henri, undated (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - John Holmer, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in OV 21) (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Winslow Homer, undated (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Charles Hopkinson, undated (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Edward Hopper, 1924, undated; (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 72-75)
  - Doris Humphrey, undated (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Sidney Hunt, 1923-1927 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Harry Jackson; G. W. James, III; Roland G. James, undated (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Mitchell Jamieson, 1942-1954, undated (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Richard Jansen, undated (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - C. Paul Jennewein; George Jensen, undated (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Avery Johnson; Erle Loran Johnson, undated (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Joseph Jones, 1938, undated (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Robert Edmond Jones, 1932, undated (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Charles Kaeselau; John Kane, undated (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - Morris Kantor, undated (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - Bernard Karfiol, undated (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Georges Kars, undated (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - Rockwell Kent, 1933, undated (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - Fiske Kimball; M. Kisling, undated (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - Georgina Klitgaard, undated (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - George Kratina; John F. Kraushaar, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 15) (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - Henry Kreis, undated; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 93-94)
  - Harald Kreutzberg, undated (Box 7, Folder 95)
  - Leon Kroll, undated (Box 7, Folder 96)
  - Max Kuehne, 1944, undated (Box 7, Folder 97)
  - Walt Kuhn, undated (Box 7, Folder 98)
  - Yasuo Kuniyoshi, 1941, undated (Box 7, Folder 99)
  - Gaston Lachaise; John LaFarge; Richard Lahey, undated (Box 7, Folder 100)
  - Pierre LaPrade; Robert Laurent, undated (Box 7, Folder 101)
  - Tom Lea; Henri Lebasque, undated (Box 7, Folder 102)
  - Arthur Lee; Doris Lee; Jules Lefebvre, undated (Box 7, Folder 103)
  - Fernand Leger; Henri Le Sidaner, undated (Box 7, Folder 104)
  - Jack Levine, undated (Box 7, Folder 105)
  - André Lhote; William Littlefield, undated (Box 7, Folder 106)
  - Ward Lockwood; Frank Long, 1947, undated (Box 7, Folder 107)
  - Carlos Lopez, undated; (2 folders; (Box 7, Folder 108-109)
  - Robert Lotiron, undated (Box 7, Folder 110)
  - Folder Title, undated (Box 7)
  - Sherman C. Loudermilk, undated; (2 folders; (Box 7, Folder 111-112)
  - Maximilian Luce, undated (Box 7, Folder 113)
  - George Luks, undated; (2 folders; (Box 7, Folder 114-115)
  - Jean Lurcot; Gwen Lux, undated (Box 7, Folder 116)
  - Stewart S. MacDermott; Artistide Maillol, undated (Box 7, Folder 117)
  - Peppino Mangravite, undated (Box 7, Folder 118)
  - Paul Manship, 1933-1959, undated; (4 folders) (Box 7, Folder 119-122)
  - Jean Marchand; L. Marcoussis, undated (Box 7, Folder 123)
  - Berta Margoulies; Albert Marquet; Fred Dana Marsh, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 15) (Box 7, Folder 124)
  - Reginald Marsh, undated; (2 folders) (Box 7, Folder 125-126)
  - Fletcher Martin; Milton Marx, undated (Box 7, Folder 127)
    (Includes portrait photograph of Milton Marx)
  - Henri Matisse, 1932, undated (Box 7, Folder 128)
  - Donald Mattison, undated (Box 7, Folder 129)
  - Henry E. Mattson, undated (Box 7, Folder 130)
  - Milton Max, undated (Box 7, Folder 131)
  - Eugene McConn Photographed by Man Ray, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 132)
  - John R. McDermott, undated (Box 7, Folder 133)
  - Henry Lee McFee; Kindred McLeary, undated (Box 7, Folder 134)
  - William McVey, undated (Box 7, Folder 135)
  - Frank Mechan, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Barse Miller, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Edgar Miller; Henry Miller, 1943, undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Kenneth Hayes Miller, 1953, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Edward Millman, 1944-1964, undated; (3 folders; (Box 8, Folder 5-7)
  - Amedeo Modigliani; Ross Moffett; Herman More; Marcel Mouillot, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - William Sidney Mount; Albert K. Murray, Jerome Myers, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Frank Osborn, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - William C. Palmer, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Jules Pascin, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - James Peale; Waldo Peirce, 1935, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Charles Hovey Pepper; Pablo Picasso; Attilio Piccirilli, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Horace Pippin; Camille Pissarro, 1940, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Ogden Pleissner, 1944, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Joseph Pollet, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Henry Varnum Poor, undated; (6 folders; (Box 8, Folder 18-23)
  - Hiram Powers, 1847, undated; (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 24-25)
  - Maurice Prendergast, 1930-1955; (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 26-27)
  - Edmund Quinn, undated (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Savo Radulovic; Ellen Emmet Rand, undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
    (Includes portrait photograph of Savo Radulovic)
  - Edward Reep; Frank K. Rehn; Théophile Robert, undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
    (Includes portrait photograph of Frank Rehn)
  - Boardman Robinson, undated; (3 folders) (Box 8, Folder 31-33)
  - Theodore Robinson; Auguste Rodin; Paul Rohland, undated (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1941, undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Doris Rosenthal; Georges Rouault; Glen H. Rounds, undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Albert P. Ryder, undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Antonio Salemme; George Samerjan, undated (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Paul Sample; John Singer Sargent, undated (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Eugene Francis Savage, undated (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Bruce Wilder Saville, undated (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Concetta Scaravaglione, undated (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Katherine Schmidt; Carl Schmitz, undated (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Henry E. Schnakenberg, undated (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - James W. Seese; Charles Shannon, undated (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Charles Sheeler, 1923, undated; (4 folders; (Box 8, Folder 46-49)
  - Dwight C. Shepler, 1945, undated (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Symeon Shimin; Paul Signac; Lucien Simon, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in OV 21) (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Sidney Simon, 1945-1966, undated; (3 folders; (Box 8, Folder 52-54)
  - John Sloan; Lawrence Beall Smith, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 15; (Box 8, Folder 55)
    Includes portrait photograph of John Sloan)
  - Samuel D. Smith, undated (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Aaron Sopher, 1940-1957, undated; (2 folders) (Box 8, Folder 57-58)
  - Eugene Speicher, undated (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Francis Speight; Niles Spencer, undated (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Robert Spencer, Ralph Stackpole, Théophile Steinlen, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 15; (Box 8, Folder 61)
    Includes portrait photograph of Ralph Stackpole)
  - Joseph Stella, undated (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Maurice Sterne, undated; (3 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 15) (Box 8, Folder 63-65)
  - Alfred Stieglitz, 1946, undated (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Josef Stransky; Henry Strater, undated (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Sara Mildred Strauss, undated (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Dudley V. Talcott; Chuzo Tamotzu, undated (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Frederic Taubes; Pavel Tchelitchew; Harry F. Tepker, undated (Box 8, Folder 70)
  - Elizabeth Terrell; F. C. Trucksess, undated (Box 8, Folder 71)
  - Harry S Truman, undated (Box 8, Folder 72)
  - Allen Tucker, 1928-1946, undated; (4 folders) (Box 8, Folder 73-76)
  - Buk Ulreich, undated (Box 8, Folder 77)
  - Leon Underwood, undated (Box 8, Folder 78)
  - Maurice Utrillo, undated (Box 8, Folder 79)
  - Kees Van Dongen; Dorothy Varian; Henri Verge-Sarrat, undated (Box 8, Folder 80)
  - Frede Jensen Vidar, undated; (3 folders; (Box 8, Folder 81-83)
  - Rudof C. Von Ripper, 1944, undated; (2 folders; (Box 8, Folder 84-85)
  - Horatio Walker, undated (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Abraham Walkowitz; Heinz Warneke, 1916, undated (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Nan Watson, 1915-1960, undated; (12 folders) (Box 8, Folder 88-99)
  - Max Weber, 1969, undated; (2 folders) (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
  - Adolph Weinman, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Elmer Wexler, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Vera White; Frederic Allen Whiting, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney; Isabel Whitney, undated; (Oversized Material Housed in Box 15) (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Mildred Williams; Andrew Winter, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - John Kellogg Woodruff; Harold Holmes Wrenn, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Mahonri Young, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - William Zorach, 1940, undated; (2 folders; Oversized Material Housed in Box 15; (Box 9, Folder 10-11)